Jan Karon papers MSS 16077
University of Virginia, Special Collections Dept.
- Personal and Family Papers
  - Personal and Family correspondence
    - Personal Correspondence - Dan Jordan, former head of the Thomas Jefferson Foundation (Monticello) and his wife, and Lou Jordan, who is an artist (4 folders), 2004-2016; 4 folder(s) (Box 80)
    - Personal Correspondence – Cathy Kane, Mitford Book Club (2 folders), 2009-2016; 2 folder(s) (Box 80)
    - Personal Correspondence – Bob Klausmeier, former book editor at Lion Publishing and Augsburg Fortress, 1994-1995; 1 folder(s) (Box 80, Folder 7)
    - Personal Correspondence – Susan Lankenau family, 2000-2012; 1 folder(s) (Box 80, Folder 8)
    - Personal Correspondence – K. Edward Lay, professor emeritus of architecture, University of Virginia, 2001-2008; 1 folder(s) (Box 80, Folder 9)
    - Personal Correspondence – Margaret and Dennis Lehmann, 1997-2011; 1 folder(s) (Box 81, Folder 1)
    - Personal Correspondence – Margaret and Dennis Lehmann, 2013-2014; 1 folder(s) (Box 81, Folder 2)
    - Personal Correspondence – Sydney L. McDowell, 1992-2014; 1 folder(s) (Box 81, Folder 3)
    - Personal Correspondence – Loonis McGlohon (1921-2002), American songwriter and jazz pianist, 1995-2001; 1 folder(s) (Box 81, Folder 4)
    - Personal Correspondence – McKinney & Silver friends and associates, 1989-2013; 1 folder(s) (Box 81, Folder 5)
    - Personal Correspondence – Leah C. Morgan, 2002-2014; 1 folder(s) (Box 81, Folder 6)
    - Personal Correspondence – Bruce R. Murray and James B. Murray, 2000-2015; 1 folder(s) (Box 81, Folder 7)
    - Personal Correspondence – Paula F. Newcomb, former director of development and public affairs for the Thomas Jefferson Foundation (1993-2004) and President of Virginia National Bank Trust (2008-2013), 2001-2010; 1 folder(s) (Box 81, Folder 8)
    - Personal Correspondence – Paula F. Newcomb, former director of development and public affairs for the Thomas Jefferson Foundation (1993-2004) and President of Virginia National Bank Trust (2008-2013), 2011-2015; 1 folder(s) (Box 81, Folder 9)
    - Personal Correspondence – Philanthropy (4 folders), 1999-2016; 4 folder(s) (Box 82)
    - Personal Correspondence – Etta Phillips, grade school teacher of Jan Karon, 1998-2006; 1 folder(s) (Box 82, Folder 5)
    - Personal Correspondence – Mae Swanner Ray (1918-2010), friend and former neighbor in Raleigh, North Carolina, 1986-2007; 1 folder(s) (Box 82, Folder 6)
    - Personal Correspondence – Jerry Richardson, businessman and owner of the NFL team, the Carolina Panthers, and his wife, Rosalind Richardson (3 folders), 2000-2016; 3 folder(s) (Box 82)
    - Personal Correspondence – Mary Williams Richardson (1914-2009), friend and former neighbor in Raleigh, North Carolina, and mother of Jerry Richardson (3 folders), 1992-1999; 3 folder(s) (Box 83)
    - Personal Correspondence – Dora Jessie Saint, pen name, Miss Read (1913-2012), 1994-2001; 1 folder(s) (Box 83, Folder 4)
    - Personal Correspondence – Helen G. Vennard, long-time friend and Martin Agency vice president and executive assistant; she joined the agency in 1970, 1989-2012; 1 folder(s) (Box 83, Folder 5)
    - Personal Correspondence – VIP and Author File (1 of 2 folders), 1997-2016; 1 folder(s) (Box 83, Folder 6)
      Correspondents include: Ann Baer, English author; Robin and Gerald Baliles (1940- ), former first lady and governor of Virginia; Rosalynn Carter (1927- ); Lynn A. Coffey, Appalachian folklorist; Kenneth Elzinga, professor and author (1942- ); North Carolina State Senator, Virginia Foxx (1943- ); Bill Gaither (1936- ) and Gloria Gaither (1942- ), singers and songwriters; Roxane Gilmore, professor and former first lady of Virginia; Renee Grisham, wife of John Grisham; U.S. Senator, Orrin G. Hatch (1934- ); Lady Bird Johnson, former first lady (1912-2007); Patricia Kluge (1948- ), former wife of John Kluge and vineyard owner; J.B. Lawrence, mayor of Blowing Rock, North Carolina, and Lynn Lawrence; Bill Leslie, musician; Calder Loth, architectural historian; and Tricia Thompson Lott, wife of Senator Lott.
    - Personal Correspondence – VIP and Author File (2 of 2 folders), 1997-2016; 1 folder(s) (Box 83, Folder 7)
      Correspondents include: Mark McEwen (1954- ), TV and radio personality; Martha S. McIntosh, editor of the Jan Karon’s Mitford Cookbook & Kitchen Reader; Ruth Moose, author; Edmund Morris, author; Leanne Payne (1932-2015), author; Rose Bampton Pelletier (1907-2007), opera singer; Condoleeza Rice (1954- ), Secretary of State; Lynda Bird Johnson Robb (1944- ), former first lady of Virgina; Mark D. Rodgers, chief of staff for Senator Rick Santorum; Martha Sundquist, former first lady of Tennessee; Steve Wasserman; Martha Williamson; Lauren Winner, author; Anne R. Worrell; and Marly Youmans, author.
    - Personal Correspondence – Walter Wangerin, Jr. (1944- ), American author and educator, [2000]-2002; 1 folder(s) (Box 83, Folder 8)
    - Personal Correspondence – Laura Watts Family, 1992-2011; 1 folder(s) (Box 83, Folder 9)
    - Personal Correspondence – John Weems, 1995; 1 folder(s) (Box 83, Folder 10)
  - Personal papers
    - Articles, Quotations, etc. kept by Jan Karon, 1994-2015; 1 folder(s) (Box 84, Folder 1)
    - Business Cards and Brochures, 1992-2010; 1 folder(s) (Box 84, Folder 2)
    - Calendar/Diary (5 volumes), 1981, 1986, 1995-1997; 5 Volumes (Box 84)
    - Calendar/Diary - Desk Calendar (3 oversize volumes), 1996-1998; 3 Volumes (Oversize box 3, Oversizefolder 8)
    - Calendar/Diary (7 volumes), 2000-2007; 7 Volumes (Box 84)
    - Calendar/Diary (8 volumes), 2008-2015; 8 Volumes (Box 85)
    - Desires and Dreams, 1978-1997; 1 folder(s) (Box 86, Folder 1)
    - Drawings by Jan Karon, 1990, 1998, undated; 1 folder(s) (Box 86, Folder 2)
    - Drawing by Jan Karon – “Breathe” color I-pad art poster (oversize), [2015]; 1 folder(s) (Oversize box 3, Oversizefolder 9)
    - Drawings given to Jan Karon, undated; 1 folder(s) (Box 86, Folder 3)
    - General, 1996-2015; 1 folder(s) (Box 86, Folder 4)
    - Hudson High School 1954 Class Reunion, 1994; 1 folder(s) (Box 86, Folder 5)
    - Inspiration, 1993, 1997, undated; 1 folder(s) (Box 86, Folder 6)
    - Journal of Brenda W. Furman, describing the family gathering at Esmont for the House Blessing and reunion, with an explanatory note dated January 26, 2016, by Jan Karon, 2003 October 30-November 2; 1 folder(s) (Box 86, Folder 7)
    - Keepsakes, 1918-2016; 1 folder(s) (Box 86, Folder 8)
    - News clippings and Printed Material, circa 1985-2014; 1 folder(s) (Box 86, Folder 9)
    - Notes, Instructions and Errand Lists, 1995, 2008-1026; 1 folder(s) (Box 86, Folder 10)
    - Pets (1 of 2 folders), 2014; 1 folder(s) (Box 86, Folder 11)
    - Pets (2 of 2 folders), 2014; 1 folder(s) (Box 86, Folder 12)
    - Photographs of Jan Karon, including publicity shots and one with President George Herbert Walker Bush and a mounted photograph of Jan Karon marching with other ladies to integrate lunch counters in Charlotte, North Carolina, [1960], 1976-2012; 1 folder(s) (Box 86, Folder 13)
    - Photographs of Family and Friends with Jan Karon, [1928?]-1996, undated; 1 folder(s) (Box 86, Folder 14)
    - Spiritual Journal, 1980; 1 folder(s) (Box 86, Folder 15)
    - Weather Journal, 1994-1996; 1 folder(s) (Box 86, Folder 16)
    - Work Station Design, undated; 1 folder(s) (Box 86, Folder 17)
- Advertising Career Materials, including NC Campaign
  - A.C. Monk & Company, Farmville, North Carolina, later Monk Austin, undated; 1 folder(s) (Box 87, Folder 1)
  - Advertising – Miscellaneous, 1969-1991; 1 folder(s) (Box 87, Folder 2)
  - Advertising Posters for Allison, AAR Powerboss, Biltmore Estate, Ethyl Corporation, Nationwide Insurance, and NCNB National Bank, 17 posters (oversize), 1989-1990; 1 folder(s) (Oversize box 1, Oversizefolder 10)
  - Advertising Posters for North Carolina Division of Travel and Tourism, 12 posters and copies (oversize), undated; 1 folder(s) (Oversize box 1, Oversizefolder 11)
  - Advertising Posters for Fogleman & Partners, Piedmont Airlines, Prentice Hydro-Ax, Stevens Gulistan Carpet, and US West Communications, 12 posters and copies (oversize), 1986-1991; 1 folder(s) (Oversize box 1, Oversizefolder 12)
  - Awards for Advertising Work, 1985-1989; 1 folder(s) (Box 87, Folder 3)
  - Benihana The Japanese Steakhouse, 1986; 1 folder(s) (Box 87, Folder 4)
  - "The Big Click: Photographs of One Day in North Carolina" – ads promoting the event, 1989; 1 folder(s) (Box 87, Folder 5)
  - Bost Bread Bakery [Continental Baking Company] copy and ads, 1986-1987; 1 folder(s) (Box 87, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, including congratulatory letters concerning the Steven E. Kelly Award, 1976-1988; 1 folder(s) (Box 87, Folder 7)
  - Gideon Ridge Inn, Blowing Rock, North Carolina – ad campaign by Jan Karon, 1994-1996; 1 folder(s) (Box 87, Folder 8)
  - Good ads, examples, 1989-1994; 1 folder(s) (Box 87, Folder 9)
  - Ivey's, undated; 1 folder(s) (Box 87, Folder 10)
  - Kent-Coffey Room Designs, Laney & Smith, Inc., 1964, undated; 1 folder(s) (Box 87, Folder 11)
  - Kohler & Campbell Pianos, undated; 1 folder(s) (Box 87, Folder 12)
  - McKinney & Silver article in "Graphis" by Dick Calderhead and "Communication Arts" by Mill Roseman, 1987, 1989; 1 folder(s) (Box 87, Folder 13)
  - Medic Computer Systems – Autochart, undated; 1 folder(s) (Box 87, Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous Clients, 1965; 1 folder(s) (Box 87, Folder 15)
  - Nationwide Insurance, 1993; 1 folder(s) (Box 87, Folder 16)
  - News clippings concerning Jan Karon’s advertising career and the Steven E. Kelly Award, 1985-1987 April; 1 folder(s) (Box 87, Folder 17)
  - News clippings concerning Jan Karon’s advertising career and the Steven E. Kelly Award, 1987 May-1989; 1 folder(s) (Box 87, Folder 18)
  - News clippings concerning Jan Karon’s advertising career and the Steven E. Kelly Award (oversize), 1987; 1 folder(s) (Oversize box 1, Oversizefolder 13)
  - North Carolina Ad Campaign – Background Stories and General materials, 1987-1988; 1 folder(s) (Box 88, Folder 1)
  - North Carolina Ad Campaign – Beaches and Coasts research (1of 2 folders), 1986-1987; 1 folder(s) (Box 88, Folder 2)
  - North Carolina Ad Campaign – Beaches and Coasts research (2 of 2 folders), 1986-1987; 1 folder(s) (Box 88, Folder 3)
  - North Carolina Ad Campaign – Cities research, undated; 1 folder(s) (Box 88, Folder 4)
  - North Carolina Ad Campaign – Copy ideas, resources, and general, 1985-1987; 1 folder(s) (Box 88, Folder 5)
  - North Carolina Ad Campaign – Crafts research, 1985 February; 1 folder(s) (Box 88, Folder 6)
  - North Carolina Ad Campaign – Festivals and Events research, 1985-1987; 1 folder(s) (Box 88, Folder 7)
  - North Carolina Ad Campaign – Folklore research, 1983-1987; 1 folder(s) (Box 88, Folder 8)
  - North Carolina Ad Campaign –Homes and villages research, 1979-1987; 1 folder(s) (Box 88, Folder 9)
  - North Carolina Ad Campaign – Ideas, lines, etc., 1981-1988; 1 folder(s) (Box 88, Folder 10)
  - North Carolina Ad Campaign – Inns and Mills and Country Stores research, undated; 1 folder(s) (Box 88, Folder 11)
  - North Carolina Ad Campaign – Midlands research, 1987; 1 folder(s) (Box 88, Folder 12)
  - North Carolina Ad Campaign – Mountains, 1984-1987; 1 folder(s) (Box 88, Folder 13)
  - North Carolina Ad Campaign – Mountains, concepts and research, undated; 1 folder(s) (Box 89, Folder 1)
  - North Carolina Ad Campaign – Music and Dance research, 1980-1988; 1 folder(s) (Box 89, Folder 2)
  - North Carolina Ad Campaign – Native Americans research, 1986-1987; 1 folder(s) (Box 89, Folder 3)
  - North Carolina Ad Campaign – Outer Banks research, 1987; 1 folder(s) (Box 89, Folder 4)
  - North Carolina Ad Campaign – Roots and early settlers research, 1985-1987; 1 folder(s) (Box 89, Folder 5)
  - North Carolina Ad Campaign – Statistics and Research, 1984-1987; 1 folder(s) (Box 89, Folder 6)
  - Norwegian Caribbean Lines, 1988; 1 folder(s) (Box 89, Folder 7)
  - Photographs from the McKinney Advertising years (3 oversize photographs), undated; 1 folder(s) (Oversize box 1)
  - Photographs of Jan Karon during her advertising career, 1975-1978; 1 folder(s) (Box 89, Folder 8)
  - Piedmont Airlines, undated; 1 folder(s) (Box 89, Folder 9)
  - Resume and Client Letters, 1977-1993; 1 folder(s) (Box 89, Folder 10)
  - Royal Caribbean Cruises, 1986-1995; 1 folder(s) (Box 89, Folder 11)
  - Stephen E. Kelly Award, 1986-1987; 1 folder(s) (Box 89, Folder 12)
  - “Tierra” Press Kit, Laney-Smith, early 1960's; 1 folder(s) (Box 89, Folder 13)
  - Tobacco Associates Inc., undated; 1 folder(s) (Box 89, Folder 14)
  - Travel Advertisements, Others, 1986-1988; 1 folder(s) (Box 89, Folder 15)
  - The Woods [currently Carolina Woods] Apartments, Winston Salem, undated; 1 folder(s) (Box 89, Folder 16)
  - Worldtex, Inc., 1990-1995; 1 folder(s) (Box 90, Folder 1)
- Topical Files
  - Barbara Bush Foundation for Family Literacy, 2006; 1 folder(s) (Box 90, Folder 2)
  - The Beatrix Potter Society, 1997-2001; 1 folder(s) (Box 90, Folder 3)
  - The Beatrix Potter Society Newsletters (3 folders), 1997-2002; 3 folder(s) (Box 90)
  - Blowing Rock, North Carolina and the Blowing Rock Historical Society, including a copy of a forward that Jan Karon wrote for "Post Cards of Historic Blowing Rock", 1998-2002; 1 folder(s) (Box 90, Folder 7)
  - "The Blowing Rocket," Blowing Rock, North Carolina, 1995-2000; 1 folder(s) (Box 90, Folder 8)
  - Book Clubs, 1994-2001; 1 folder(s) (Box 90, Folder 9)
  - Book Cover Art Purchases by Jan Karon, 1998-2000; 1 folder(s) (Box 90, Folder 10)
  - Books to Read, 2002; 1 folder(s) (Box 90, Folder 11)
  - The Chelsea Forum, Inc., 1997-2002; 1 folder(s) (Box 90, Folder 12)
  - Child Advocacy Institute, North Carolina, 1998; 1 folder(s) (Box 90, Folder 13)
  - Diploma, High School Equivalency, 1975; 1 folder(s) (Box 91, Folder 1)
  - Dogs, 1998-1999; 1 folder(s) (Box 91, Folder 2)
  - Employee Files, 2000-2004; 1 folder(s) (Box 91, Folder 3)
  - Employee Files - Victoria Dunham, 2005-2007; 1 folder(s) (Box 91, Folder 4)
  - The Episcopal Church, 1995-2000; 1 folder(s) (Box 90, Folder 5)
  - Farmington Member Art Show, 2014 December-2015 January; 1 folder(s) (Box 91, Folder 6)
  - Farmington Member Art Show, 2015 January-2016; 1 folder(s) (Box 91, Folder 7)
  - The Fellowship of Christ the Savior, Blowing Rock, North Carolina, 1996-1998; 1 folder(s) (Box 91, Folder 8)
  - Financial and Legal Papers, 1985-2016; 1 folder(s) (Box 91, Folder 9)
  - Genealogy of George Washington Wilson and Jane Caroline Miller, undated; 1 folder(s) (Box 91, Folder 10)
  - Graham Project, 1999; 1 folder(s) (Box 92, Folder 1)
  - Harry M. Jacobs, Jr., member of the Advertising Hall of Fame, biographical information, 2005, 2014 July; 1 folder(s) (Box 92, Folder 2)
    Also includes a letter from Harry M. Jacobs, Jr., May 6, 2005, and his wife, Bobbi Jacobs, July 6, 2014, to Jan Karon.
  - Lenoir, North Carolina, 1998; 1 folder(s) (Box 92, Folder 3)
  - Miss Fannie’s Happiness Fund, 1997-1998; 1 folder(s) (Box 92, Folder 4)
  - Mitford - General (6 folders), 1994-2008; 6 folder(s) (Box 92)
  - Mitford Appreciation Society (4 folders), 1997-2004; 4 folder(s) (Box 93)
    Includes information about a meeting held at Once Upon a Time, a bookstore in Montrose, California, in 1997.
  - Mitford, Barony of, Northumberland, England, 1991-2003; 1 folder(s) (Box 93, Folder 5)
  - Mitford Christmas Books and Christmas Catalog proposal, 2003; 1 folder(s) (Box 93, Folder 6)
  - Mitford Fan Site, 2007; 1 folder(s) (Box 93, Folder 7)
  - Mitford film proposals (2 folders), 1996-2015; 2 folder(s) (Box 93)
  - Mitford Calendar Proposals (with an example for 1998), 1998-2004; 1 folder(s) (Box 94, Folder 1)
  - Mitford newsletters, 1996-2005; 1 folder(s) (Box 94, Folder 2)
  - Mitford newsletters- correspondence and supporting material, 1996-1999; 1 folder(s) (Box 94, Folder 3)
  - Mitford newsletters- correspondence and supporting material, 2000-2005; 1 folder(s) (Box 94, Folder 4)
  - Mitford – sketches of the church office and the rectory drawn by Jan Karon, undated; 1 folder(s) (Box 94, Folder 5)
  - Monticello (3 folders), 2000-2016; 3 folder(s) (Box 94)
  - Monticello Cabinet (4 folders), 1999-2015; 4 folder(s) (Box 95)
  - Monticello –Invitations (General), 2000-2006, 2014; 1 folder(s) (Box 95, Folder 5)
  - Monticello/Thomas Jefferson Foundation Tour of Italy, 2015 May; 1 folder(s) (Box 95, Folder 6)
  - National Trust and Land Preservation, 1998-1999; 1 folder(s) (Box 95, Folder 7)
  - Obituaries, chiefly United Kingdom, but also includes one for Claude Ray (Toby) Setzer, Lelia Hobson Bovard and Betty Parker Coleman, 1996-2016; 1 folder(s) (Box 96, Folder 1)
  - On-line birthday party for Jan Karon, 2001 March; 1 folder(s) (Box 96, Folder 2)
  - Passports, 1981-2006; 1 folder(s) (Box 96, Folder 3)
  - Prayer Team during the writing of "Home to Holly Springs", 2006; 1 folder(s) (Box 96, Folder 4)
  - Read Aloud Book Proposal, 2004-2005; 1 folder(s) (Box 96, Folder 5)
  - Readers guides for the Mitford Years series, 1996-2003; 1 folder(s) (Box 96, Folder 6)
  - Research for the Mitford Years series – articles and biographies, 1996-2002; 1 folder(s) (Box 96, Folder 7)
  - Research file for Father Tim character, 1975-1996, undated; 1 folder(s) (Box 96, Folder 8)
  - “Rosegate,” Blowing Rock, North Carolina, 1988-2004; 1 folder(s) (Box 96, Folder 9)
  - St. Anne’s Parish, Albemarle County, Virginia, including a color photograph of Jan Karon used in the church directory, 2000-2002; 1 folder(s) (Box 96, Folder 10)
  - "Stirling Bridge" newsletters, 1996-1998; 1 folder(s) (Box 96, Folder 11)
  - Thanksgiving, chiefly recipes, 1982-1988; 1 folder(s) (Box 96, Folder 12)
  - Research Books - references to Father Tim’s childhood in Holly Springs, Mississippi, marked throughout the eight previous Karon books, including a history of Holly Springs, also marked throughout, used in the writing of "Home to Holly Springs", 1994-2006; 1 Hollinger boxes (Box 97)
    Pages marked in "At Home in Mitford" include pages 3, 4, 5, 47, 68, 77, 101, 104, 114, 162, 181, 182, 207, 227, 234, 241, 259, 264, 281, 293, 297, 328, 354, 368, 373, 403, and 405. Pages marked in "A Common Life" include page 6. Pages marked in "A New Song" include pages 1, 34, 40, 45, 51, 67, 74, 78, 89, 117, 125, 161, 195, 206, 208, 212, 231, 235, 247, 253, 262, 263, 266, 267, 269, 285, 296, 297, 300, 385, and 399. Pages marked in "In This Mountain" include pages 12, 41, 61, 80, 89, 91, 95, 97, 108, 124, 138, 139, 197, 240, 242, 262, 287, 302, 304, and 381. Pages marked in "Light from Heaven" include pages 8, 15, 28, 39, 79, 106, 114, 144, 153, 213, 215, 234, 277, 366, and 383. Pages marked in "Shepherds Abiding" include pages 18, 25, 88, 115, 127, 142, 164, and 245. Pages marked in "These High Green Hills" include pages 2, 50, 71, 98, 102, 109, 147, 154, 158, 167, 209, 247, 259, 270, and 308. Pages marked in "My Hometown Growing Up in Holly Springs, Mississippi" by Lois Swaney include pages 21, 46, 51, 59, 63, 67, 70, 88, 101, and 102. Also present is a folder of inserts removed from the research books, 2006-2007.
  - Travel - Caribbean Cruise, 1994; 1 folder(s) (Box 98, Folder 1)
  - Travel – Central American trip of Candace Freeland, 1987-1988; 1 folder(s) (Box 98, Folder 2)
  - Travel- England – Printed Material, 1986-1987; 1 folder(s) (Box 98, Folder 3)
  - Travel- England – Printed Material, 1987; 1 folder(s) (Box 98, Folder 4)
  - Travel- England – Printed Material - Accommodations, 1996; 1 folder(s) (Box 98, Folder 5)
  - Travel- England – Printed Material - Accommodations, 1996; 1 folder(s) (Box 98, Folder 6)
  - Travel- England – Printed Material, including guide books, 1996; 1 folder(s) (Box 98, Folder 7)
  - Travel- England – Printed Material, including guide books, 1996, 2003; 1 folder(s) (Box 98, Folder 8)
  - Travel - Florida, 2016; 1 folder(s) (Box 99, Folder 1)
  - Travel- Ireland, 2007-2008; 1 folder(s) (Box 99, Folder 2)
  - Travel- Ireland, 2010-2011; 1 folder(s) (Box 99, Folder 3)
  - Travel – Ireland Notebook (1 of 2 folders), 2008; 1 folder(s) (Box 99, Folder 4)
  - Travel – Ireland Notebook (2 of 2 folders), 2008; 1 folder(s) (Box 99, Folder 5)
  - Travel – Ireland – Printed Material, 2008-2009; 1 folder(s) (Box 99, Folder 6)
  - Travel- Ireland – Travel Log of a trip with Jan Karon kept by Diane Wright, 2008 July 15-August 3; 1 folder(s) (Box 99, Folder 7)
  - Travel - Portugal, 2015; 1 folder(s) (Box 99, Folder 8)
  - Travel-Wales – Printed Material, 1996; 1 folder(s) (Box 99, Folder 9)
  - Typefaces, 1993; 1 folder(s) (Box 99, Folder 10)
  - University of Virginia Library – Alderman Library and Special Collections Staff, 2000-2008; 1 folder(s) (Box 99, Folder 11)
  - University of Virginia Library – Alderman Library and Special Collections Staff, 2011-2016; 1 folder(s) (Box 100, Folder 1)
  - University of Virginia – Professor James Hunter and the Center on Religion and American Democracy, 2000-2001; 1 folder(s) (Box 100, Folder 2)
  - University of Virginia – In Media Res Foundation, 2006; 1 folder(s) (Box 100, Folder 3)
  - University of Virginia – Rotunda Society, 1999-2000; 1 folder(s) (Box 100, Folder 4)
  - Virginia Historical Society, 2006-2007; 1 folder(s) (Box 100, Folder 5)
  - Website (2 folders), 2001-2010; 2 folder(s) (Box 100)
  - Writers and Writing (3 folders), 1986-1999, undated; 3 folder(s) (Box 100)
- Esmont Architectural Drawings and Papers
  - Architectural Drawings, chiefly of Esmont
    - Esmont – Architectural Drawings – Preliminary Study, Alterations and Additions for Kelly Graham by Johnson, Craven & Gibson, 4 oversize sheets, 1953; 1 folder(s) (Oversize folder flat file 1)
    - Esmont – Architectural Drawings – Alterations and Additions, Kitchen Layout, Kitchen Porch, Book Shelving, and Water System, for Kelly Graham by Johnson, Craven & Gibson, 4 oversize sheets, 1953-1954; 1 folder(s) (Oversize folder flat file 2)
    - Esmont – Architectural Drawings – House Alterations and Additions for Mr. and Mrs. F.S. Cornell, Plans, Elevations, and Details by Baker, Heyward & Llorens, 10 sheets and Barn, Utility Building, Cattle Shed and Sealed Storage Units by Harvestore Products, 3 oversize sheets, 1963-1964; 1 folder(s) (Oversize folder flat file 3)
    - Esmont – Architectural Drawings – Schedule of Drawings – DEPG, 18 oversize sheets, 2001 May; 1 folder(s) (Oversize folder flat file 4)
    - Esmont – Architectural Drawings – Schedule of Drawings – DEPG, 23 oversize sheets, 2001 May-June; 1 folder(s) (Oversize folder flat file 5)
    - Esmont – Architectural Drawings – Schedule of Drawings – DEPG, 33 oversize sheets, 2001 May-July; 1 folder(s) (Oversize folder flat file 6)
    - Esmont – Architectural Drawings – Schedule of Drawings – DEPG, 36 oversize sheets, 2001 May-September; 1 folder(s) (Oversize folder flat file 7)
    - Esmont – Architectural Drawings – Guest House, Floor Plans, Elevations, Fireplace and Chimney, DEPG, 8 oversize sheets, 2000; 1 folder(s) (Oversize folder flat file 8)
    - Esmont – Architectural Drawings – Site Plans, DEPG, 11 oversize sheets, 2001-2002; 1 folder(s) (Oversize folder flat file 9)
    - Esmont – Architectural Drawings – Chapel, Plans, Sections, Elevations, and Details, DEPG, 6 oversize sheets, undated; 1 folder(s) (Oversize folder flat file 10)
    - Esmont – Architectural Drawings – Chapel, colored representative drawings with perspective, [DEPG], 4 oversize sheets, undated; 1 folder(s) (Oversize folder flat file 11)
    - Esmont – Architectural Drawings – Topographic Surveys, Trueline Surveying, Inc., 9 oversize sheets or copies, with one marked in red, undated; 1 folder(s) (Oversize folder flat file 12)
    - Esmont – Architectural Drawings – Mechanical and Electrical Drawings for the House and Property, DEPG, 9 oversize sheets, 2001-2003; 1 folder(s) (Oversize folder flat file 13)